# **DUNCAN J. MAYER, Ph.D.**

Doylestown Pennsylvania, 18901

609.571.5739 · DuncanMayer77@gmail.com

Personal Website · Github · LinkedIn · ORCID

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a social scientist and statistician with experience leading analytic portfolios with academic, government, and private sector stakeholders to understand complex behavior and other phenomena. I maintain good coding practices and am comfortable building, evaluating, and interpreting everything from well known algorithms to bespoke models. I excel at research dissemination, I have published 13 academic papers and have experience communicating results and recommendations to audiences with a range of technical sophistication. My full academic CV can be found here.

#### **SKILLS**

Quantitative Longitudinal Data Analysis, Hierarchical Models, Spatial Statistics, Bayesian Methodologies

Qualitative: Focus Groups, Interviews, Content Analysis, and Case Studies

Programming: R (9 years) | SQL (4 years) | Stan (4 years)

### RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**US Citizenship and Immigration Services, Department of Homeland Security** 

Social Science Analyst (full-time)

Camp Springs, MD

August 2024 - Present

As a social scientist in USCIS's Policy Research and Evaluation Division I led retrospective and prospective studies of policy changes within the US immigration system. Among others, I worked with large and complex administrative data, and teams with diverse backgrounds, to evaluate changes to work authorization and the civics naturalization exam. I disseminated results in papers and briefed agency leadership on study findings.

BeVera Solutions

Atlanta, GA

Health Statistician (full-time)

Sept. 2022 - August 2024

In a client facing role as a statistician at a consulting firm I contributed to project proposals, provided statistical support and consultation, and led and managed the methodological development of studies addressing internal questions for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. I collaborated with CDC staff to elicit important questions, led outcome evaluations of COVID19 vaccine programs within federal agencies and studies of health equity during the nation's COVID19 vaccine roll out.

## **Case Western Reserve University**

Research fellow (full-time)

Cleveland, OH Aug. 2018 – June. 2022

As a research fellow with the Center on Poverty and Community Development I developed and led a research portfolio focused on novel quantitative methodologies and empirical studies of the distribution of community resources using modern computational methods. I disseminated the results of these projects in academic journals and presentations to academic and external audiences.

#### **EDUCATION**

Case Western Reserve University

PhD in Social Welfare

Cleveland, OH August 2023

Marywood University

Scranton, PA May 2017

Masters of Social Work Bachelors of Social Work

May 2015

;